James A. Ingalls Papers 1992.0045
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
James A. Ingalls Papers
undated, 1916-1996
1992.0045
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
30.0 Linear feet
Contracts, correspondence, legal records, financial records, newspaper clippings and notes gathered and generated by James A. Ingalls, a field representative for the International Union of Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers, AFL-CIO, from the 1950s to the 1992. Materials give details from when Ingalls represented Connecticut local chapters to negotiate contracts, resolve strikes and lockouts, and develop collective bargaining agreements, pension plans and compensation and health benefits packages.
Ingalls, James A.
Biography of James A. Ingall
James A. Ingalls, born on September 23, 1922, of East Granby, Connecticut, was a Field Representative of the International Union of Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers, AFL-CIO, from the 1950s to 1992.
James A. Ingalls died on November 22, 1998, in Flagler, Florida.
Scope and Content
The papers consist of materials generated and gathered by James A. Ingalls when he served as a Field Representative of the International Union of Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers, AFL-CIO. They include contracts, correspondence, legal records, financial records, newspaper clippings and notes from when Ingalls represented Connecticut local chapters to negotiate contracts, resolve strikes and lockouts, and develop collective bargaining agreements, pension plans and compensation and health benefits packages.
Connecticut companies (and their corresponding locals) include Acme Electric of Cuba, New York, American Optical of Hartford (local 408), Ametek in West Hartford (local 281), Atlantic Machine Tools in Newington, Bowser Technical Refrigeration, Bridgeport Metal Goods of Bridgeport (local 237), Brunswick Corp. of Torrington (local 247), Bussmann Division of McGraw-Edison of Bristol (local 260), Carlyle Johnson Machine Co. of Manchester (local 281), Connecticut Telephone & Electric Corporation of Meriden (local 285), Eagle Lock & Screw Company (local 256), V.C.A. Division of Ethyl Corp. in Bridgeport (local 238), Fenn Manufacturing Co. of Newington (local 266), Gray & Prior Machine Co. of Bloomfield (local 281), Hanson-Whitney Co. of Hartford (local 295), H.P. Townsend Mfg. Co. of West Hartford (local 281), Hi-G Co. Inc. of Windsor Locks (local 280), Ingraham Industries of Bristol (local 260), Keeney Manufacturing Co. of Newington (local 215), Kingfisher of Vernon, Merrow Machine Co. of Hartford (local 249), New England Carbide (local 257), Sculli Machine Co. of East Hartford (local 281), Sessions Clock Company in Forestville (local 261), Son-Chief Electronics in Winsted (local 212), Terry Corporation (local 289), Union Hardware Division of Brunswick Corporation of Torrington (local 247), Woodside Precision Corp. (local 256), and Yankee Metal Product Corp. of Norwalk (local 245).
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut labor. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Provenance and Acquisition
The Papers were donated to the University of Connecticut by James A. Ingalls in 1992.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers.; Administrative Records.; By-Laws.; Connecticut Labor--Strikes and lockouts.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Electric industries--Connecticut.; Electric industry workers--Connecticut.; Electric industry workers--Labor unions--Connecticut.; Financial Records.; Grievance procedures--Connecticut.; Labor leaders--Connecticut.; Newspaper clippings.; Notes.; Photographs.; Publications.; Strikes and lockouts--Electric industry--Connecticut.
- Series I: Inventory, 1916-1996
  - Papers of negotiations of the following Connecticut companies and their corresponding locals: Atlantic Machine Tools in Newington, Bowser Technical Refrigeration, Connecticut Telephone & Electric Corporation of Meriden (local 285), Eagle Lock & Screw Company (local 256), Sessions Clock Company in Forestville (local 261), Son-Chief Electronics in Winsted (local 212), Terry Corporation (local 289), Woodside Precision Corp. (local 256), 1952-1972 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Newspaper clippings, Publications, Administrative Records, Notes, Correspondence, Manuscripts
  - Atlantic Machine Tools in Newington, Bowser Technical Refrigeration, Connecticut Telephone & Electric Corporation of Meriden (local 285), Eagle Lock & Screw Company (local 256), Sessions Clock Company in Forestville (local 261), Son-Chief Electronics in Winsted (local 212), Terry Corporation (local 289), and Woodside Precision Corp. (local 256), 1958-1973 (Box 2)
    Publications, Correspondence, News Clippings, Notes, Photographs
  - Eagle Lock of Terryville (local 256, includes information about a strike and lockout in 1975), Gray & Prior Machine Co. of Bloomfield (local 281), H.P. Townsend Mfg. Co. of West Hartford (local 281), Hi-G Co. Inc. of Windsor Locks (local 280), and Merrow Machine Co. of Hartford (local 249), 1975-1983 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, Publications, Administrative Records, Notes, News Clippings, Fliers, Manuscripts
  - Brunswick Corp. of Torrington (local 247), Carlyle Johnson Machine Co. of Manchester (local 281), Eagle Lock & Screw Co. (local 256, includes a scrapbook of newspaper clippings about 1975 strike); Hanson-Whitney Co. of Hartford (local 295), and Sculli Machine Co. of East Hartford (local 281), 1954-1983 (Box 4)
    News Clippings, Publications, Manuscripts, Notes, Correspondence, Financial and Administrative Records
  - New England Carbide (local 257), Hi-G Co. Inc. of Windsor Locks (lopcal 280), and Terry Corporation and Terry Steam Turbine Company (local 289); also includes an arbitration manual from the IUE Education Department, 1968-1982 (Box 5)
    Notes, Publications, Correspondence, Administrative Records, News Clippings, Financial Records
  - Fenn Manufacturing Co. of Newington (local 266), Carlyle Johnson Machine Co. of Manchester (local 281), Merrow Machine Co. of Hartford (local 249), and Union Hardware, affiliated with Brunswick Corporation (local 247), 1974-1981 (Box 6)
    Publications, Correspondence, Notes, Newspaper Clippings, Administrative Records
  - Kingfisher of Vernon, American Optical of Hartford (local 408), Eagle Lock of Plymouth (local 256) including strike materials from 1975, Ingraham Industries of Bristol (local 260), and general IUE organization newsletters, memos, and flyers, and a Union steward's manual, 1950-1975 (Box 7)
    Notes, Correspondence, Manuscripts, Publications, Fliers, Financial and Administrative Records, Newspaper Clippings
  - IUE leadership and trainng manuals from national office and District 2 (New England), 1961-1964 (Box 8)
    Publications, Books
  - Union Hardware Division of Brunswick Corporation of Torrington (local 247), Merrow Machine Corp. of Hartford (local 249) including information about a 1967 strike, Keeney Manufacturing Co. of Newington (local 215), Bridgeport Metal Goods of Bridgeport (local 237), 1967-1979 (Box 9)
    Notes, Correspondence, Publications, News Clippings, Administrative and Financial Records,
  - Whitlock Plant of Ametek in West Hartford (local 281), V.C.A. Division of Ethyl Corp. in Bridgeport (local 238), Yankee Metal Product Corp. of Norwalk (local 245), Bussmann Division of McGraw-Edison of Bristol (local 260), Carlyle Johnson Machine Co. of Manchester (local 281), Hanson-Whitney Co. of Hartford (local 295), 1967-1996 (Box 10)
    Notes, Correspondences, Publications, Administrative and Financial Records
  - Newspapers and magazines recounting the death of John F. Kennedy; Hanson-Whitney in Hartford (local 281) including information about a strike in 1954 (includes photographs); Sessions Clock Co. of Bristol, including information about charges of police brutality to strikers (1967); Ingraham Co. of Bristol (Local 260), and Union Hardware of Torrington (local 247), 1953-1969 (Box 11)
    Photographs, Correspondence, Publications, Notes, News Clippings, Financial and Administrative Records
  - Sessions Clock Company in Forestville (local 261), Connecticut Telephone and Electric Corp. (local 285), Gray Manufacturing in Hartford (local 297) -- include photograph of a 1954 union meeting, Eagle Lock (local 256), Ingraham Company in Bristol (local 260), Acme Electric of Cuba, New York, Bulk, 1951-1979; 1916-1979 (Box 12)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Publications, Correspondences, Notes, News Clippings, Photographs
  - Information about labor legislation, IUE Skilled Trade Program, Statistical and Tactical Information Report, State AFL-CIO, 1950-1983 (Box 13)
    Publications, Administrative Records, Notes, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence
  - State Board of Mediation and Arbitration, Solidarity Day, Manufacturing Company Retirement Plan, International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers Memorandum, Labor Management Records, political campaigns in 1976 and 1980 of Toby Moffett (Congressman for Connecticut's 6th district), 1957-1983 (Box 14)
    Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Correspondence, Administrative Records
  - Proceedings of the IUE Conventions, Officers reports for the conventions, Delegates education sourcebook on major issues, 1949-1982 (Box 15)
    Books, Publications, Awards
  - Constitutions and by-laws, agreements, pension plans, and benefits plans of locals, 1943-1983 (Box 16)
    Publications
  - Manuals for stewards, arbitration, and leadership and how to conduct grievances and strikes, committee records, 1949-1978 (Box 17)
    Books, Publications and Newspaper Clippings
  - IUE Bulletins, IUE contract negotiations, safety bulletins, training seminars, organizing strikes, arbitration manual, and election materials, 1953-1980 (Box 18)
    Publications, Correspondence, Notes, Newspaper Clippings
  - IUE Policy, Comparative Survey of Major Collective Bargaining Agreements, Manual for shop stewards, Connecticut State Labor Council meeting proceedings, 1944-1982 (Box 19)
    Books, Publications, Newspaper Clippings
  - Whitlock Manufacturing in West Hartford (local 281), Connecticut Telephone Co. (local 285), information about General Electric Company strike (1969-1970) in New York, 1968-1985 (Box 20)
    Notes, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, Publications, Administrative and Financial Records
  - Labor Relations, Electing Union Officers, Help for the Working Wounded, Department of Labor Occupational Safety Standards (1974), 1948-1978 (Box 21)
    Books, Publications, Notes